
> word-search-adventure@0.0.0 test
> node --experimental-strip-types --test tests/*.test.mjs

✔ Stage 1 no longer grants walk-over shards anywhere on the board (51.6189ms)
✔ hint progresses, survives focus switch, caps before last letter and hides completed (1.9486ms)
✔ long hints never expose full spelling (0.7081ms)
✔ scan queries every matching tile including distractors, expires without mutating tile states (4.2121ms)
✔ invalid full input never charges; uppercase normalization accepts exactly ASCII letter (0.7121ms)
✔ no shards and selection/feedback lock guard both request paths (0.688ms)
✔ valid no-match scan costs one and active scans replace rather than stack (14.6906ms)
✔ actual stage transition carries player ledger and resets stage-owned assistance (1.2006ms)
✔ door reveal stays backed by full plaster on every frame; OPEN reveals an opaque recess (712.5282ms)
✔ perimeter meshes leave all letter footprints clear throughout room reactions at the fixed camera angle (903.5597ms)
✔ BOOK reacts across the shelf before the featured book, then settles without lighting other props (37.3037ms)
✔ KEY materializes by the player and its world position converges on a moving player (9.6276ms)
✔ forest props do not occlude board, player or feedback from the unchanged camera (137.2585ms)
✔ crossing landings leave the full reserved river span empty and stay clear of the grid (28.0352ms)
KEY: (0,0) -> (0,1) -> (0,2)
LIGHT: (0,4) -> (1,4) -> (2,4) -> (3,4) -> (4,4)
WATER: (2,0) -> (2,1) -> (2,2) -> (3,2) -> (4,2)
BOOK: (4,0) -> (4,1) -> (5,1) -> (5,2)
DOOR: (3,6) -> (2,6) -> (1,6) -> (0,6)
OPEN: (5,3) -> (5,4) -> (6,4) -> (6,5)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: KEY (3.5953ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: LIGHT (1.2236ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: WATER (0.7027ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: BOOK (7.2165ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: DOOR (0.4736ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: OPEN (0.4547ms)
✔ cardinal neighbors only (0.386ms)
✔ deterministic IDs and world/grid round trips at different cell sizes (6.1253ms)
✔ hover never overwrites selection; correct expires and reset cancels feedback (1.1622ms)
✔ malformed stage layout fails early (1.3074ms)
✔ one command interpolates then commits exactly one tile and stops (4.2861ms)
✔ reject diagonal, malformed and all four boundary commands (6.6413ms)
✔ stage start validated and completion independent of update frequency (0.8355ms)
✔ keyboard press only, first event wins, no queue, aliases and teardown (3.6502ms)
✔ arrival builds KEY, backtracks; mid-step release submits only committed path (1.7274ms)
✔ OPEN locked, not remembered; DOOR unlocks once; presentation then discovered list (9.4514ms)
✔ malformed dependency data is rejected (0.7043ms)
✔ key flight is simulation-owned, once only, and completes after 1.8 seconds (0.6627ms)
✔ legacy exit helper remains isolated from the stage runtime (1.3993ms)
✔ key tracks player, shelf slides, lamps stagger, droplets end and healthy plant persists (50.876ms)
✔ E input rejects repeat, typing and modifiers; release, blur and teardown work (14.399ms)
✔ five available data-driven clues contain no own target; navigation wraps and preserves progress (4.2595ms)
✔ non-focused WATER completes; wrong and duplicate keep focus/progress and emit no completion (7.9385ms)
✔ focused completion waits for feedback, skips completed, supports revisiting and manual override (0.6036ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders complete exactly once with no stage transition (206.2113ms)
✔ quest policy rejects vocabulary words without a quest and malformed quest mappings (13.1779ms)
✔ river stays inside reserved zone, below land and clear of the letter grid (37.7644ms)
✔ flow advances gently, stays in water across wrap and releases owned GPU resources (54.8761ms)
✔ current-tile start, KEY, immutable submission and no double submit (4.0125ms)
✔ backtrack immediately, preserve invalid path, disallow reuse, recover (0.8393ms)
✔ coordinate tracking reads committed logical grid; hover cannot mutate path (20.125ms)
✔ real input adapter: left mouse, capture, release outside, blur, visibility, cancel and teardown (6.3247ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; KEY last (6.1126ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; LIGHT last (1.034ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; WATER last (0.6605ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; BOOK last (0.6551ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; OPEN last (0.8186ms)
✔ empty placeholder does not complete (0.3374ms)
✔ transition locks, fades, disposes old state, mounts fresh state once, then fades in (2.1824ms)
✔ disposing during fade prevents mounting a new stage (0.8584ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: KEY (427.1071ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: LIGHT (196.6533ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: WATER (71.2291ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: BOOK (56.4573ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: OPEN (49.3631ms)
✔ intro receives destination data and blocks mounting, duplicate next and start until it finishes (0.9989ms)
✔ disposing during intro prevents destination gameplay from mounting (1.8747ms)
✔ offset grid round trips, stays safely on main ground, and supports original movement (6.6895ms)
✔ river foundation and raised ground fit the unchanged camera without a crossing (51.6542ms)
✔ CLIMB first does not strand unfinished words; readiness waits for reactions, feedback and a committed step (4.5055ms)
✔ all 49 grid starts walk through the bridge and root waypoints without teleporting or rewriting gameplay (63.6762ms)
✔ ending can start safely from every existing traversal node; timing is frame-rate independent (49.74ms)
✔ the existing completion overlay waits until summit arrival plus a 0.75-second pause, once only (2.0234ms)
✔ wood has distinct grain/edges; narrow rope bridge assembles existing boards and consumes the coil (204.0774ms)
✔ ending route stays on supporting geometry and within the unchanged desktop/narrow camera (154.8298ms)
✔ initial hidden locks, both material orders, Hint gates, construction completion and one-time NEW QUEST (22.2786ms)
✔ safe crossing, grid return, far-side routes, climb gate, summit height and invalid moves (2.6711ms)
✔ completion waits for final reactions, duplicate submissions/events do not replay, reset is fresh (9.4064ms)
✔ visual reactions consume the same planks, keep mesh count bounded, and reconstruct final state (64.623ms)
✔ bridge and root route nodes have visible supporting surfaces; new geometry avoids letters (88.3003ms)
✔ RIVER emphasis changes currents temporarily without affecting movement; Stage 1 remains grid-only (30.5184ms)
✔ TREE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (16.7196ms)
✔ WOOD: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (1.5007ms)
✔ ROPE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (1.4067ms)
✔ RIVER: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (2.0181ms)
✔ BRIDGE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (0.8133ms)
✔ CLIMB: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (1.7484ms)
✔ four initial clues, generic progressive hints after dependencies, scan includes every decoy R (2.0276ms)
✔ start is a decoy; diagonals rejected; forest reactions preserve the tested board (2.253ms)
✔ Space and mouse hold/release submit once, exclude each other, cancel on blur, dispose cleanly (2.4358ms)
✔ Stage 2 uses the existing intro flow to mount the Stage 3 vocabulary runtime (10.6837ms)
✔ frozen Stage 3.2 board, spawn, camera and layout remain unchanged (4.1569ms)
✔ initial hidden quests reject submissions/hints; independent scan; exact unlock banners (22.1109ms)
✔ reaction durations, duplicates, reset and no replay after completed submission (3.0172ms)
✔ all 720 word attempt orders converge under existing dependency validation (225.6439ms)
✔ CARRY before CLOCK waits safely; ending waits for feedback and committed movement (1.2595ms)
✔ all 49 starts move continuously via pickup and destination without rewriting player/grid state (32.653ms)
✔ completion waits for delivery plus pause, emits once and large/small time steps agree (1.157ms)
✔ town rendering is a bounded idempotent projection with readable prop identities (46.1853ms)
✔ shop pulse, letter hover/receive and clock emphasis settle without accumulating transforms (22.1132ms)
✔ one full board uses original cardinal movement and cannot leave any edge (6.5592ms)
✔ all landmarks and every letter fit the fixed frame with no building covering a letter (98.0056ms)
✔ mouse/Space holds, WASD/arrows, release and blur keep original selection behavior (15.2302ms)
✔ town BREAD: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (9.8591ms)
✔ town COIN: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.0145ms)
✔ town SHOP: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (0.6571ms)
✔ town LETTER: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (0.8738ms)
✔ town CLOCK: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.3137ms)
✔ town CARRY: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.8868ms)
✔ town has four initial clues, prefix hints after dependencies and a scan that includes decoys (3.4679ms)
✔ town spawn is a decoy, diagonals fail, all quests complete in dependency order without cottage world changes (30.5986ms)
✔ Stage 3 transitions through the existing intro to an empty, non-completing Stage 4 (4.5785ms)
✔ workshop fits desktop/narrow frames and leaves every letter surface unobstructed (142.5603ms)
✔ two reachable support objectives require explicit inspection, grant once and preserve main state (4.1493ms)
✔ reward crystal only appears after inspection and clears with reward timer (7.4132ms)
✔ support definitions reject duplicate IDs and invalid rewards (3.2704ms)
✔ normalizes targets, submissions and completed words; rejects non-target English words (2.0319ms)
✔ all six real board paths resolve; correct tiles persist, cleanup allows reuse, duplicates do not progress (7.1856ms)
✔ backtrack does not validate before release; wrong and interrupted feedback preserve progress (2.4673ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: KEY (5.0777ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: LIGHT (1.8582ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: WATER (0.38ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: BOOK (0.3641ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: DOOR (0.3529ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: OPEN (0.3162ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders converge, duplicate/wrong submissions and events never replay (72.6842ms)
✔ renderer projects supplied state safely and normal door opening animates (36.7841ms)
ℹ tests 121
ℹ suites 0
ℹ pass 121
ℹ fail 0
ℹ cancelled 0
ℹ skipped 0
ℹ todo 0
ℹ duration_ms 3876.5701
