
> word-search-adventure@0.0.0 test
> node --experimental-strip-types --test tests/*.test.mjs

✔ Stage 1 no longer grants walk-over shards anywhere on the board (35.9173ms)
✔ hint progresses, survives focus switch, caps before last letter and hides completed (2.308ms)
✔ long hints never expose full spelling (1.7834ms)
✔ scan queries every matching tile including distractors, expires without mutating tile states (6.3788ms)
✔ invalid full input never charges; uppercase normalization accepts exactly ASCII letter (3.1355ms)
✔ no shards and selection/feedback lock guard both request paths (1.6658ms)
✔ valid no-match scan costs one and active scans replace rather than stack (0.6012ms)
✔ actual stage transition carries player ledger and resets stage-owned assistance (3.9404ms)
✔ door reveal stays backed by full plaster on every frame; OPEN reveals an opaque recess (2392.008ms)
✔ perimeter meshes leave all letter footprints clear throughout room reactions at the fixed camera angle (2581.5021ms)
✔ BOOK reacts across the shelf before the featured book, then settles without lighting other props (33.1147ms)
✔ KEY materializes by the player and its world position converges on a moving player (21.7363ms)
✔ forest props do not occlude board, player or feedback from the unchanged camera (340.505ms)
✔ crossing landings leave the full reserved river span empty and stay clear of the grid (43.4854ms)
KEY: (0,0) -> (0,1) -> (0,2)
LIGHT: (0,4) -> (1,4) -> (2,4) -> (3,4) -> (4,4)
WATER: (2,0) -> (2,1) -> (2,2) -> (3,2) -> (4,2)
BOOK: (4,0) -> (4,1) -> (5,1) -> (5,2)
DOOR: (3,6) -> (2,6) -> (1,6) -> (0,6)
OPEN: (5,3) -> (5,4) -> (6,4) -> (6,5)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: KEY (20.1171ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: LIGHT (0.9082ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: WATER (4.3506ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: BOOK (2.1978ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: DOOR (1.3438ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: OPEN (0.9853ms)
✔ cardinal neighbors only (0.9448ms)
✔ deterministic IDs and world/grid round trips at different cell sizes (5.5235ms)
✔ hover never overwrites selection; correct expires and reset cancels feedback (3.6627ms)
✔ malformed stage layout fails early (5.2895ms)
✔ one command interpolates then commits exactly one tile and stops (14.3999ms)
✔ reject diagonal, malformed and all four boundary commands (2.98ms)
✔ stage start validated and completion independent of update frequency (14.9387ms)
✔ keyboard press only, first event wins, no queue, aliases and teardown (3.6883ms)
✔ arrival builds KEY, backtracks; mid-step release submits only committed path (4.0447ms)
✔ OPEN locked, not remembered; DOOR unlocks once; presentation then discovered list (13.3183ms)
✔ malformed dependency data is rejected (0.991ms)
✔ key flight is simulation-owned, once only, and completes after 1.8 seconds (1.4112ms)
✔ legacy exit helper remains isolated from the stage runtime (4.583ms)
✔ key tracks player, shelf slides, lamps stagger, droplets end and healthy plant persists (96.7281ms)
✔ E input rejects repeat, typing and modifiers; release, blur and teardown work (6.6712ms)
✔ five available data-driven clues contain no own target; navigation wraps and preserves progress (21.4491ms)
✔ non-focused WATER completes; wrong and duplicate keep focus/progress and emit no completion (33.0771ms)
✔ focused completion waits for feedback, skips completed, supports revisiting and manual override (0.7706ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders complete exactly once with no stage transition (283.7207ms)
✔ quest policy rejects vocabulary words without a quest and malformed quest mappings (2.9308ms)
✔ river stays inside reserved zone, below land and clear of the letter grid (206.0635ms)
✔ flow advances gently, stays in water across wrap and releases owned GPU resources (168.0995ms)
✔ current-tile start, KEY, immutable submission and no double submit (13.6144ms)
✔ backtrack immediately, preserve invalid path, disallow reuse, recover (7.3224ms)
✔ coordinate tracking reads committed logical grid; hover cannot mutate path (7.1649ms)
✔ real input adapter: left mouse, capture, release outside, blur, visibility, cancel and teardown (13.4639ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; KEY last (131.5659ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; LIGHT last (1.6571ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; WATER last (7.7767ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; BOOK last (0.9509ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; OPEN last (1.0245ms)
✔ empty placeholder does not complete (0.4768ms)
✔ transition locks, fades, disposes old state, mounts fresh state once, then fades in (5.4354ms)
✔ disposing during fade prevents mounting a new stage (26.9894ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: KEY (483.6759ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: LIGHT (399.4279ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: WATER (497.9931ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: BOOK (93.548ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: OPEN (66.8678ms)
✔ intro receives destination data and blocks mounting, duplicate next and start until it finishes (4.7587ms)
✔ disposing during intro prevents destination gameplay from mounting (1.3304ms)
✔ offset grid round trips, stays safely on main ground, and supports original movement (17.5541ms)
✔ river foundation and raised ground fit the unchanged camera without a crossing (422.0444ms)
✔ CLIMB first does not strand unfinished words; readiness waits for reactions, feedback and a committed step (16.5791ms)
✔ all 49 grid starts walk through the bridge and root waypoints without teleporting or rewriting gameplay (287.9528ms)
✔ ending can start safely from every existing traversal node; timing is frame-rate independent (78.4842ms)
✔ the existing completion overlay waits until summit arrival plus a 0.75-second pause, once only (1.4048ms)
✔ wood has distinct grain/edges; narrow rope bridge assembles existing boards and consumes the coil (436.0567ms)
✔ ending route stays on supporting geometry and within the unchanged desktop/narrow camera (470.1463ms)
✔ initial hidden locks, both material orders, Hint gates, construction completion and one-time NEW QUEST (12.5365ms)
✔ safe crossing, grid return, far-side routes, climb gate, summit height and invalid moves (37.4853ms)
✔ completion waits for final reactions, duplicate submissions/events do not replay, reset is fresh (34.6992ms)
✔ visual reactions consume the same planks, keep mesh count bounded, and reconstruct final state (268.505ms)
✔ bridge and root route nodes have visible supporting surfaces; new geometry avoids letters (391.9879ms)
✔ RIVER emphasis changes currents temporarily without affecting movement; Stage 1 remains grid-only (13.604ms)
✔ TREE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (47.0879ms)
✔ WOOD: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (8.0885ms)
✔ ROPE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (3.1135ms)
✔ RIVER: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (5.1406ms)
✔ BRIDGE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (3.6761ms)
✔ CLIMB: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (1.5209ms)
✔ four initial clues, generic progressive hints after dependencies, scan includes every decoy R (6.7703ms)
✔ start is a decoy; diagonals rejected; forest reactions preserve the tested board (11.2316ms)
✔ Space and mouse hold/release submit once, exclude each other, cancel on blur, dispose cleanly (12.8946ms)
✔ Stage 2 uses the existing intro flow to mount the Stage 3 vocabulary runtime (17.1394ms)
✔ frozen Stage 3.2 board, spawn, camera and layout remain unchanged (8.2531ms)
✔ initial hidden quests reject submissions/hints; independent scan; exact unlock banners (5.9672ms)
✔ reaction durations, duplicates, reset and no replay after completed submission (2.2736ms)
✔ all 720 word attempt orders converge under existing dependency validation (676.1699ms)
✔ CARRY before CLOCK waits safely; ending waits for feedback and committed movement (8.8038ms)
✔ all 49 starts move continuously via pickup and destination without rewriting player/grid state (71.7687ms)
✔ completion waits for delivery plus pause, emits once and large/small time steps agree (16.963ms)
✔ town rendering is a bounded idempotent projection with readable prop identities (120.4267ms)
✔ shop pulse, letter hover/receive and clock emphasis settle without accumulating transforms (26.5235ms)
✔ one full board uses original cardinal movement and cannot leave any edge (10.8049ms)
✔ all landmarks and every letter fit the fixed frame with no building covering a letter (190.0944ms)
✔ mouse/Space holds, WASD/arrows, release and blur keep original selection behavior (11.985ms)
✔ town BREAD: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (32.2751ms)
✔ town COIN: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (2.9501ms)
✔ town SHOP: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.6263ms)
✔ town LETTER: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.2094ms)
✔ town CLOCK: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (39.4701ms)
✔ town CARRY: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.1884ms)
✔ town has four initial clues, prefix hints after dependencies and a scan that includes decoys (23.2376ms)
✔ town spawn is a decoy, diagonals fail, all quests complete in dependency order without cottage world changes (27.4367ms)
✔ two reachable support objectives require explicit inspection, grant once and preserve main state (13.5284ms)
✔ reward crystal only appears after inspection and clears with reward timer (16.9803ms)
✔ support definitions reject duplicate IDs and invalid rewards (1.7158ms)
✔ normalizes targets, submissions and completed words; rejects non-target English words (4.061ms)
✔ all six real board paths resolve; correct tiles persist, cleanup allows reuse, duplicates do not progress (8.2123ms)
✔ backtrack does not validate before release; wrong and interrupted feedback preserve progress (2.1888ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: KEY (10.8709ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: LIGHT (2.5022ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: WATER (2.2064ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: BOOK (1.3588ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: DOOR (4.1548ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: OPEN (2.0556ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders converge, duplicate/wrong submissions and events never replay (265.7501ms)
✔ renderer projects supplied state safely and normal door opening animates (108.7953ms)
ℹ tests 119
ℹ suites 0
ℹ pass 119
ℹ fail 0
ℹ cancelled 0
ℹ skipped 0
ℹ todo 0
ℹ duration_ms 7556.8137
