
> word-search-adventure@0.0.0 test
> node --experimental-strip-types --test tests/*.test.mjs

✔ Stage 1 no longer grants walk-over shards anywhere on the board (11.0259ms)
✔ hint progresses, survives focus switch, caps before last letter and hides completed (1.5802ms)
✔ long hints never expose full spelling (0.6282ms)
✔ scan queries every matching tile including distractors, expires without mutating tile states (2.665ms)
✔ invalid full input never charges; uppercase normalization accepts exactly ASCII letter (0.7405ms)
✔ no shards and selection/feedback lock guard both request paths (0.4801ms)
✔ valid no-match scan costs one and active scans replace rather than stack (0.5289ms)
✔ actual stage transition carries player ledger and resets stage-owned assistance (1.8447ms)
✔ door reveal stays backed by full plaster on every frame; OPEN reveals an opaque recess (427.6923ms)
✔ perimeter meshes leave all letter footprints clear throughout room reactions at the fixed camera angle (819.9391ms)
✔ BOOK reacts across the shelf before the featured book, then settles without lighting other props (18.3745ms)
✔ KEY materializes by the player and its world position converges on a moving player (9.8535ms)
✔ forest props do not occlude board, player or feedback from the unchanged camera (170.7519ms)
✔ crossing landings leave the full reserved river span empty and stay clear of the grid (37.9688ms)
KEY: (0,0) -> (0,1) -> (0,2)
LIGHT: (0,4) -> (1,4) -> (2,4) -> (3,4) -> (4,4)
WATER: (2,0) -> (2,1) -> (2,2) -> (3,2) -> (4,2)
BOOK: (4,0) -> (4,1) -> (5,1) -> (5,2)
DOOR: (3,6) -> (2,6) -> (1,6) -> (0,6)
OPEN: (5,3) -> (5,4) -> (6,4) -> (6,5)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: KEY (7.7875ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: LIGHT (2.3799ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: WATER (4.4516ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: BOOK (0.4985ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: DOOR (0.4486ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: OPEN (0.5169ms)
✔ cardinal neighbors only (0.4149ms)
✔ deterministic IDs and world/grid round trips at different cell sizes (3.247ms)
✔ hover never overwrites selection; correct expires and reset cancels feedback (0.8996ms)
✔ malformed stage layout fails early (0.7613ms)
✔ one command interpolates then commits exactly one tile and stops (4.6295ms)
✔ reject diagonal, malformed and all four boundary commands (1.0855ms)
✔ stage start validated and completion independent of update frequency (1.1179ms)
✔ keyboard press only, first event wins, no queue, aliases and teardown (1.6086ms)
✔ arrival builds KEY, backtracks; mid-step release submits only committed path (1.7849ms)
✔ OPEN locked, not remembered; DOOR unlocks once; presentation then discovered list (5.0682ms)
✔ malformed dependency data is rejected (0.6941ms)
✔ key flight is simulation-owned, once only, and completes after 1.8 seconds (0.7053ms)
✔ legacy exit helper remains isolated from the stage runtime (1.5058ms)
✔ key tracks player, shelf slides, lamps stagger, droplets end and healthy plant persists (47.0752ms)
✔ E input rejects repeat, typing and modifiers; release, blur and teardown work (3.0788ms)
✔ five available data-driven clues contain no own target; navigation wraps and preserves progress (3.7803ms)
✔ non-focused WATER completes; wrong and duplicate keep focus/progress and emit no completion (5.8076ms)
✔ focused completion waits for feedback, skips completed, supports revisiting and manual override (0.6882ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders complete exactly once with no stage transition (138.1335ms)
✔ quest policy rejects vocabulary words without a quest and malformed quest mappings (0.8384ms)
✔ river stays inside reserved zone, below land and clear of the letter grid (28.9123ms)
✔ flow advances gently, stays in water across wrap and releases owned GPU resources (15.6013ms)
✔ current-tile start, KEY, immutable submission and no double submit (7.6227ms)
✔ backtrack immediately, preserve invalid path, disallow reuse, recover (0.7437ms)
✔ coordinate tracking reads committed logical grid; hover cannot mutate path (2.5928ms)
✔ real input adapter: left mouse, capture, release outside, blur, visibility, cancel and teardown (2.6061ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; KEY last (7.5002ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; LIGHT last (0.8811ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; WATER last (0.5251ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; BOOK last (0.5775ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; OPEN last (0.5557ms)
✔ empty placeholder does not complete (0.3126ms)
✔ transition locks, fades, disposes old state, mounts fresh state once, then fades in (1.4669ms)
✔ disposing during fade prevents mounting a new stage (2.1317ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: KEY (173.4006ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: LIGHT (50.8819ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: WATER (43.156ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: BOOK (58.2188ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: OPEN (102.8689ms)
✔ intro receives destination data and blocks mounting, duplicate next and start until it finishes (1.4699ms)
✔ disposing during intro prevents destination gameplay from mounting (0.7748ms)
✔ offset grid round trips, stays safely on main ground, and supports original movement (5.747ms)
✔ river foundation and raised ground fit the unchanged camera without a crossing (69.0847ms)
✔ CLIMB first does not strand unfinished words; readiness waits for reactions, feedback and a committed step (4.3061ms)
✔ all 49 grid starts walk through the bridge and root waypoints without teleporting or rewriting gameplay (44.1093ms)
✔ ending can start safely from every existing traversal node; timing is frame-rate independent (6.7191ms)
✔ the existing completion overlay waits until summit arrival plus a 0.75-second pause, once only (6.7989ms)
✔ wood has distinct grain/edges; narrow rope bridge assembles existing boards and consumes the coil (81.6883ms)
✔ ending route stays on supporting geometry and within the unchanged desktop/narrow camera (119.1075ms)
✔ initial hidden locks, both material orders, Hint gates, construction completion and one-time NEW QUEST (13.1203ms)
✔ safe crossing, grid return, far-side routes, climb gate, summit height and invalid moves (2.6111ms)
✔ completion waits for final reactions, duplicate submissions/events do not replay, reset is fresh (2.2784ms)
✔ visual reactions consume the same planks, keep mesh count bounded, and reconstruct final state (54.1591ms)
✔ bridge and root route nodes have visible supporting surfaces; new geometry avoids letters (70.8998ms)
✔ RIVER emphasis changes currents temporarily without affecting movement; Stage 1 remains grid-only (4.8099ms)
✔ TREE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (9.7878ms)
✔ WOOD: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (0.9673ms)
✔ ROPE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (0.6279ms)
✔ RIVER: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (0.7076ms)
✔ BRIDGE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (0.8074ms)
✔ CLIMB: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (3.2676ms)
✔ four initial clues, generic progressive hints after dependencies, scan includes every decoy R (7.7647ms)
✔ start is a decoy; diagonals rejected; forest reactions preserve the tested board (3.1202ms)
✔ Space and mouse hold/release submit once, exclude each other, cancel on blur, dispose cleanly (12.8142ms)
✔ Stage 2 uses the existing intro flow to mount the Stage 3 vocabulary runtime (6.3124ms)
✔ frozen Stage 3.2 board, spawn, camera and layout remain unchanged (3.4748ms)
✔ initial hidden quests reject submissions/hints; independent scan; exact unlock banners (12.734ms)
✔ reaction durations, duplicates, reset and no replay after completed submission (1.9163ms)
✔ all 720 word attempt orders converge under existing dependency validation (255.3715ms)
✔ CARRY before CLOCK waits safely; ending waits for feedback and committed movement (1.0509ms)
✔ all 49 starts move continuously via pickup and destination without rewriting player/grid state (26.4311ms)
✔ completion waits for delivery plus pause, emits once and large/small time steps agree (1.1021ms)
✔ town rendering is a bounded idempotent projection with readable prop identities (82.3424ms)
✔ shop pulse, letter hover/receive and clock emphasis settle without accumulating transforms (39.3987ms)
✔ one full board uses original cardinal movement and cannot leave any edge (15.1558ms)
✔ all landmarks and every letter fit the fixed frame with no building covering a letter (65.3333ms)
✔ mouse/Space holds, WASD/arrows, release and blur keep original selection behavior (19.1921ms)
✔ town BREAD: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (9.4514ms)
✔ town COIN: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.0618ms)
✔ town SHOP: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.2867ms)
✔ town LETTER: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (0.9728ms)
✔ town CLOCK: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.0327ms)
✔ town CARRY: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (0.9837ms)
✔ town has four initial clues, prefix hints after dependencies and a scan that includes decoys (2.7489ms)
✔ town spawn is a decoy, diagonals fail, all quests complete in dependency order without cottage world changes (4.2602ms)
✔ Stage 3 transitions through the existing intro to a vocabulary Stage 4 that waits for completion (10.6493ms)
✔ workshop fits desktop/narrow frames and leaves every letter surface unobstructed (165.2714ms)
✔ workshop sequence GEAR then REPAIR: delayed STOP, smooth shutdown, once-only completion (74.2657ms)
✔ workshop sequence REPAIR then GEAR: delayed STOP, smooth shutdown, once-only completion (35.4268ms)
✔ workshop reveal waits for actual completion plus 0.45 seconds and ignores invalid dt (5.2367ms)
✔ workshop renderer projects all phases without state mutation, keeps crates on output, and preserves grid visibility (416.4192ms)
✔ polish: local gear emphasis, repair transform and sequential power arrival (11.2675ms)
✔ notification overlay hides a queued banner while reactions hold it and resumes afterward (3.7266ms)
✔ finale waits for visible word feedback, locks immediately, holds idle and preserves output until disposal (26.6662ms)
✔ Stage 4 Next Stage uses fade/dispose/Stage 5 intro/mount/fade without reloading (22.6397ms)
✔ workshop GEAR: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (56.0949ms)
✔ workshop REPAIR: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (12.75ms)
✔ workshop POWER: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (18.3236ms)
✔ workshop LEVER: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (32.0879ms)
✔ workshop START: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (33.2853ms)
✔ workshop STOP: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (19.6928ms)
✔ workshop progression with GEAR first; locked words never complete; STOP requires submission (57.1348ms)
✔ workshop progression with REPAIR first; locked words never complete; STOP requires submission (34.5378ms)
✔ workshop hints gate locked/completed quests and reveal prefixes; scan includes every matching decoy only temporarily (13.356ms)
✔ workshop spawn reaches all 49 tiles; diagonal and loop reuse rejected; approved framing unchanged (3.802ms)
✔ two reachable support objectives require explicit inspection, grant once and preserve main state (4.8806ms)
✔ reward crystal only appears after inspection and clears with reward timer (17.1343ms)
✔ support definitions reject duplicate IDs and invalid rewards (1.0306ms)
✔ normalizes targets, submissions and completed words; rejects non-target English words (2.3156ms)
✔ all six real board paths resolve; correct tiles persist, cleanup allows reuse, duplicates do not progress (10.7819ms)
✔ backtrack does not validate before release; wrong and interrupted feedback preserve progress (1.3826ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: KEY (5.8704ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: LIGHT (1.0762ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: WATER (1.3895ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: BOOK (1.6098ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: DOOR (0.945ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: OPEN (1.7783ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders converge, duplicate/wrong submissions and events never replay (106.8647ms)
✔ renderer projects supplied state safely and normal door opening animates (34.7483ms)
ℹ tests 139
ℹ suites 0
ℹ pass 139
ℹ fail 0
ℹ cancelled 0
ℹ skipped 0
ℹ todo 0
ℹ duration_ms 3077.9053
