
> word-search-adventure@0.0.0 test
> node --experimental-strip-types --test tests/*.test.mjs

✔ Stage 1 no longer grants walk-over shards anywhere on the board (3.9318ms)
✔ hint progresses, survives focus switch, caps before last letter and hides completed (1.1843ms)
✔ long hints never expose full spelling (0.6605ms)
✔ scan queries every matching tile including distractors, expires without mutating tile states (2.485ms)
✔ invalid full input never charges; uppercase normalization accepts exactly ASCII letter (0.7582ms)
✔ no shards and selection/feedback lock guard both request paths (0.5132ms)
✔ valid no-match scan costs one and active scans replace rather than stack (0.8709ms)
✔ actual stage transition carries player ledger and resets stage-owned assistance (1.5797ms)
✔ door reveal stays backed by full plaster on every frame; OPEN reveals an opaque recess (483.945ms)
✔ perimeter meshes leave all letter footprints clear throughout room reactions at the fixed camera angle (928.2077ms)
✔ BOOK reacts across the shelf before the featured book, then settles without lighting other props (29.9365ms)
✔ KEY materializes by the player and its world position converges on a moving player (16.7234ms)
✔ forest props do not occlude board, player or feedback from the unchanged camera (151.6939ms)
✔ crossing landings leave the full reserved river span empty and stay clear of the grid (15.4376ms)
KEY: (0,0) -> (0,1) -> (0,2)
LIGHT: (0,4) -> (1,4) -> (2,4) -> (3,4) -> (4,4)
WATER: (2,0) -> (2,1) -> (2,2) -> (3,2) -> (4,2)
BOOK: (4,0) -> (4,1) -> (5,1) -> (5,2)
DOOR: (3,6) -> (2,6) -> (1,6) -> (0,6)
OPEN: (5,3) -> (5,4) -> (6,4) -> (6,5)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: KEY (4.9407ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: LIGHT (1.6911ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: WATER (5.8901ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: BOOK (2.2779ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: DOOR (0.5469ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: OPEN (0.479ms)
✔ cardinal neighbors only (0.5191ms)
✔ deterministic IDs and world/grid round trips at different cell sizes (4.4018ms)
✔ hover never overwrites selection; correct expires and reset cancels feedback (22.7809ms)
✔ malformed stage layout fails early (1.9128ms)
✔ one command interpolates then commits exactly one tile and stops (4.6535ms)
✔ reject diagonal, malformed and all four boundary commands (2.5646ms)
✔ stage start validated and completion independent of update frequency (2.6657ms)
✔ keyboard press only, first event wins, no queue, aliases and teardown (3.7454ms)
✔ arrival builds KEY, backtracks; mid-step release submits only committed path (2.184ms)
✔ OPEN locked, not remembered; DOOR unlocks once; presentation then discovered list (5.9426ms)
✔ malformed dependency data is rejected (1.292ms)
✔ key flight is simulation-owned, once only, and completes after 1.8 seconds (1.2564ms)
✔ legacy exit helper remains isolated from the stage runtime (1.9694ms)
✔ key tracks player, shelf slides, lamps stagger, droplets end and healthy plant persists (74.8088ms)
✔ E input rejects repeat, typing and modifiers; release, blur and teardown work (3.1538ms)
✔ five available data-driven clues contain no own target; navigation wraps and preserves progress (4.8696ms)
✔ non-focused WATER completes; wrong and duplicate keep focus/progress and emit no completion (3.6264ms)
✔ focused completion waits for feedback, skips completed, supports revisiting and manual override (0.75ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders complete exactly once with no stage transition (201.5068ms)
✔ quest policy rejects vocabulary words without a quest and malformed quest mappings (1.1837ms)
✔ river stays inside reserved zone, below land and clear of the letter grid (26.7954ms)
✔ flow advances gently, stays in water across wrap and releases owned GPU resources (31.6593ms)
✔ current-tile start, KEY, immutable submission and no double submit (6.3067ms)
✔ backtrack immediately, preserve invalid path, disallow reuse, recover (1.2115ms)
✔ coordinate tracking reads committed logical grid; hover cannot mutate path (3.8676ms)
✔ real input adapter: left mouse, capture, release outside, blur, visibility, cancel and teardown (4.3756ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; KEY last (6.1697ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; LIGHT last (0.8737ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; WATER last (0.589ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; BOOK last (0.7033ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; OPEN last (0.8662ms)
✔ empty placeholder does not complete (0.6486ms)
✔ transition locks, fades, disposes old state, mounts fresh state once, then fades in (2.5972ms)
✔ disposing during fade prevents mounting a new stage (0.6773ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: KEY (134.4192ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: LIGHT (82.9222ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: WATER (52.7981ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: BOOK (32.9135ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: OPEN (81.1091ms)
✔ intro receives destination data and blocks mounting, duplicate next and start until it finishes (1.6696ms)
✔ disposing during intro prevents destination gameplay from mounting (32.2159ms)
✔ offset grid round trips, stays safely on main ground, and supports original movement (6.2688ms)
✔ river foundation and raised ground fit the unchanged camera without a crossing (65.7751ms)
✔ CLIMB first does not strand unfinished words; readiness waits for reactions, feedback and a committed step (6.0532ms)
✔ all 49 grid starts walk through the bridge and root waypoints without teleporting or rewriting gameplay (73.5702ms)
✔ ending can start safely from every existing traversal node; timing is frame-rate independent (6.2163ms)
✔ the existing completion overlay waits until summit arrival plus a 0.75-second pause, once only (1.6532ms)
✔ wood has distinct grain/edges; narrow rope bridge assembles existing boards and consumes the coil (63.0818ms)
✔ ending route stays on supporting geometry and within the unchanged desktop/narrow camera (112.4324ms)
✔ initial hidden locks, both material orders, Hint gates, construction completion and one-time NEW QUEST (16.3647ms)
✔ safe crossing, grid return, far-side routes, climb gate, summit height and invalid moves (2.4828ms)
✔ completion waits for final reactions, duplicate submissions/events do not replay, reset is fresh (2.4603ms)
✔ visual reactions consume the same planks, keep mesh count bounded, and reconstruct final state (48.4756ms)
✔ bridge and root route nodes have visible supporting surfaces; new geometry avoids letters (73.8077ms)
✔ RIVER emphasis changes currents temporarily without affecting movement; Stage 1 remains grid-only (9.6801ms)
✔ TREE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (7.8921ms)
✔ WOOD: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (19.7417ms)
✔ ROPE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (0.9267ms)
✔ RIVER: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (0.9003ms)
✔ BRIDGE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (1.5476ms)
✔ CLIMB: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (0.7401ms)
✔ four initial clues, generic progressive hints after dependencies, scan includes every decoy R (3.3453ms)
✔ start is a decoy; diagonals rejected; forest reactions preserve the tested board (3.1567ms)
✔ Space and mouse hold/release submit once, exclude each other, cancel on blur, dispose cleanly (2.3489ms)
✔ Stage 2 uses the existing intro flow to mount the Stage 3 vocabulary runtime (5.6019ms)
✔ frozen Stage 3.2 board, spawn, camera and layout remain unchanged (8.5271ms)
✔ initial hidden quests reject submissions/hints; independent scan; exact unlock banners (7.5053ms)
✔ reaction durations, duplicates, reset and no replay after completed submission (4.8088ms)
✔ all 720 word attempt orders converge under existing dependency validation (316.0461ms)
✔ CARRY before CLOCK waits safely; ending waits for feedback and committed movement (1.0384ms)
✔ all 49 starts move continuously via pickup and destination without rewriting player/grid state (39.4782ms)
✔ completion waits for delivery plus pause, emits once and large/small time steps agree (1.5263ms)
✔ town rendering is a bounded idempotent projection with readable prop identities (49.9024ms)
✔ shop pulse, letter hover/receive and clock emphasis settle without accumulating transforms (22.01ms)
✔ one full board uses original cardinal movement and cannot leave any edge (7.1174ms)
✔ all landmarks and every letter fit the fixed frame with no building covering a letter (85.6486ms)
✔ mouse/Space holds, WASD/arrows, release and blur keep original selection behavior (38.0588ms)
✔ town BREAD: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (14.0064ms)
✔ town COIN: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.4976ms)
✔ town SHOP: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.9219ms)
✔ town LETTER: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.827ms)
✔ town CLOCK: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.7628ms)
✔ town CARRY: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (3.1657ms)
✔ town has four initial clues, prefix hints after dependencies and a scan that includes decoys (4.3988ms)
✔ town spawn is a decoy, diagonals fail, all quests complete in dependency order without cottage world changes (2.8847ms)
✔ Stage 3 transitions through the existing intro to a vocabulary Stage 4 that waits for completion (5.5178ms)
✔ workshop fits desktop/narrow frames and leaves every letter surface unobstructed (197.5342ms)
✔ workshop sequence GEAR then REPAIR: delayed STOP, smooth shutdown, once-only completion (34.8989ms)
✔ workshop sequence REPAIR then GEAR: delayed STOP, smooth shutdown, once-only completion (10.9844ms)
✔ workshop queued reactions wait for visual prerequisites, duplicate events are idempotent and invalid dt is ignored (22.3136ms)
✔ workshop renderer projects all phases without state mutation, keeps crates on output, and preserves grid visibility (252.0679ms)
✔ workshop GEAR: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (15.3156ms)
✔ workshop REPAIR: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (23.1321ms)
✔ workshop POWER: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (7.093ms)
✔ workshop LEVER: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (7.0187ms)
✔ workshop START: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (11.0795ms)
✔ workshop STOP: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (13.6945ms)
✔ workshop progression with GEAR first; locked words never complete; STOP requires submission (18.8071ms)
✔ workshop progression with REPAIR first; locked words never complete; STOP requires submission (32.0432ms)
✔ workshop hints gate locked/completed quests and reveal prefixes; scan includes every matching decoy only temporarily (10.4506ms)
✔ workshop spawn reaches all 49 tiles; diagonal and loop reuse rejected; approved framing unchanged (4.2914ms)
✔ two reachable support objectives require explicit inspection, grant once and preserve main state (7.0549ms)
✔ reward crystal only appears after inspection and clears with reward timer (7.9578ms)
✔ support definitions reject duplicate IDs and invalid rewards (0.8539ms)
✔ normalizes targets, submissions and completed words; rejects non-target English words (2.3908ms)
✔ all six real board paths resolve; correct tiles persist, cleanup allows reuse, duplicates do not progress (7.7798ms)
✔ backtrack does not validate before release; wrong and interrupted feedback preserve progress (1.4515ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: KEY (3.4059ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: LIGHT (0.5484ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: WATER (0.4167ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: BOOK (0.4294ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: DOOR (0.4286ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: OPEN (0.375ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders converge, duplicate/wrong submissions and events never replay (98.7082ms)
✔ renderer projects supplied state safely and normal door opening animates (44.5761ms)
ℹ tests 135
ℹ suites 0
ℹ pass 135
ℹ fail 0
ℹ cancelled 0
ℹ skipped 0
ℹ todo 0
ℹ duration_ms 3376.925
