
> word-search-adventure@0.0.0 test
> node --experimental-strip-types --test tests/*.test.mjs

✔ Stage 1 no longer grants walk-over shards anywhere on the board (4.9576ms)
✔ hint progresses, survives focus switch, caps before last letter and hides completed (2.2657ms)
✔ long hints never expose full spelling (20.9249ms)
✔ scan queries every matching tile including distractors, expires without mutating tile states (7.3122ms)
✔ invalid full input never charges; uppercase normalization accepts exactly ASCII letter (2.0465ms)
✔ no shards and selection/feedback lock guard both request paths (0.9712ms)
✔ valid no-match scan costs one and active scans replace rather than stack (0.9712ms)
✔ actual stage transition carries player ledger and resets stage-owned assistance (2.4085ms)
✔ door reveal stays backed by full plaster on every frame; OPEN reveals an opaque recess (833.2876ms)
✔ perimeter meshes leave all letter footprints clear throughout room reactions at the fixed camera angle (1227.7951ms)
✔ BOOK reacts across the shelf before the featured book, then settles without lighting other props (56.5708ms)
✔ KEY materializes by the player and its world position converges on a moving player (12.2266ms)
✔ forest props do not occlude board, player or feedback from the unchanged camera (230.675ms)
✔ crossing landings leave the full reserved river span empty and stay clear of the grid (13.5537ms)
KEY: (0,0) -> (0,1) -> (0,2)
LIGHT: (0,4) -> (1,4) -> (2,4) -> (3,4) -> (4,4)
WATER: (2,0) -> (2,1) -> (2,2) -> (3,2) -> (4,2)
BOOK: (4,0) -> (4,1) -> (5,1) -> (5,2)
DOOR: (3,6) -> (2,6) -> (1,6) -> (0,6)
OPEN: (5,3) -> (5,4) -> (6,4) -> (6,5)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: KEY (9.0857ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: LIGHT (1.2902ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: WATER (32.4547ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: BOOK (1.1067ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: DOOR (0.4991ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: OPEN (0.4412ms)
✔ cardinal neighbors only (0.4228ms)
✔ deterministic IDs and world/grid round trips at different cell sizes (5.2593ms)
✔ hover never overwrites selection; correct expires and reset cancels feedback (35.2451ms)
✔ malformed stage layout fails early (18.7395ms)
✔ one command interpolates then commits exactly one tile and stops (17.1206ms)
✔ reject diagonal, malformed and all four boundary commands (1.104ms)
✔ stage start validated and completion independent of update frequency (0.9669ms)
✔ keyboard press only, first event wins, no queue, aliases and teardown (2.6971ms)
✔ arrival builds KEY, backtracks; mid-step release submits only committed path (2.3558ms)
✔ OPEN locked, not remembered; DOOR unlocks once; presentation then discovered list (16.1891ms)
✔ malformed dependency data is rejected (0.8368ms)
✔ key flight is simulation-owned, once only, and completes after 1.8 seconds (2.0617ms)
✔ legacy exit helper remains isolated from the stage runtime (8.1034ms)
✔ key tracks player, shelf slides, lamps stagger, droplets end and healthy plant persists (144.6815ms)
✔ E input rejects repeat, typing and modifiers; release, blur and teardown work (1.8989ms)
✔ five available data-driven clues contain no own target; navigation wraps and preserves progress (13.5037ms)
✔ non-focused WATER completes; wrong and duplicate keep focus/progress and emit no completion (9.8769ms)
✔ focused completion waits for feedback, skips completed, supports revisiting and manual override (0.7763ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders complete exactly once with no stage transition (251.4314ms)
✔ quest policy rejects vocabulary words without a quest and malformed quest mappings (0.94ms)
✔ river stays inside reserved zone, below land and clear of the letter grid (20.2791ms)
✔ flow advances gently, stays in water across wrap and releases owned GPU resources (57.2937ms)
✔ current-tile start, KEY, immutable submission and no double submit (4.8078ms)
✔ backtrack immediately, preserve invalid path, disallow reuse, recover (2.5466ms)
✔ coordinate tracking reads committed logical grid; hover cannot mutate path (0.5324ms)
✔ real input adapter: left mouse, capture, release outside, blur, visibility, cancel and teardown (3.206ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; KEY last (5.8729ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; LIGHT last (0.939ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; WATER last (0.8091ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; BOOK last (0.937ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; OPEN last (0.8041ms)
✔ empty placeholder does not complete (0.6839ms)
✔ transition locks, fades, disposes old state, mounts fresh state once, then fades in (29.7147ms)
✔ disposing during fade prevents mounting a new stage (4.476ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: KEY (178.7547ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: LIGHT (74.9295ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: WATER (72.9284ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: BOOK (51.6154ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: OPEN (28.3015ms)
✔ intro receives destination data and blocks mounting, duplicate next and start until it finishes (1.1518ms)
✔ disposing during intro prevents destination gameplay from mounting (0.6942ms)
✔ offset grid round trips, stays safely on main ground, and supports original movement (6.6728ms)
✔ river foundation and raised ground fit the unchanged camera without a crossing (143.0114ms)
✔ CLIMB first does not strand unfinished words; readiness waits for reactions, feedback and a committed step (4.9967ms)
✔ all 49 grid starts walk through the bridge and root waypoints without teleporting or rewriting gameplay (67.1362ms)
✔ ending can start safely from every existing traversal node; timing is frame-rate independent (7.3727ms)
✔ the existing completion overlay waits until summit arrival plus a 0.75-second pause, once only (2.0297ms)
✔ wood has distinct grain/edges; narrow rope bridge assembles existing boards and consumes the coil (124.9557ms)
✔ ending route stays on supporting geometry and within the unchanged desktop/narrow camera (162.9808ms)
✔ initial hidden locks, both material orders, Hint gates, construction completion and one-time NEW QUEST (39.9583ms)
✔ safe crossing, grid return, far-side routes, climb gate, summit height and invalid moves (2.6823ms)
✔ completion waits for final reactions, duplicate submissions/events do not replay, reset is fresh (2.1697ms)
✔ visual reactions consume the same planks, keep mesh count bounded, and reconstruct final state (100.9518ms)
✔ bridge and root route nodes have visible supporting surfaces; new geometry avoids letters (138.5294ms)
✔ RIVER emphasis changes currents temporarily without affecting movement; Stage 1 remains grid-only (7.8753ms)
✔ TREE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (7.5495ms)
✔ WOOD: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (0.9914ms)
✔ ROPE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (0.8614ms)
✔ RIVER: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (0.7272ms)
✔ BRIDGE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (1.4095ms)
✔ CLIMB: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (2.5986ms)
✔ four initial clues, generic progressive hints after dependencies, scan includes every decoy R (7.2589ms)
✔ start is a decoy; diagonals rejected; forest reactions preserve the tested board (2.3619ms)
✔ Space and mouse hold/release submit once, exclude each other, cancel on blur, dispose cleanly (5.1958ms)
✔ Stage 2 uses the existing intro flow to mount the Stage 3 vocabulary runtime (5.2044ms)
✔ frozen Stage 3.2 board, spawn, camera and layout remain unchanged (8.5178ms)
✔ initial hidden quests reject submissions/hints; independent scan; exact unlock banners (9.1747ms)
✔ reaction durations, duplicates, reset and no replay after completed submission (1.7491ms)
✔ all 720 word attempt orders converge under existing dependency validation (204.0803ms)
✔ CARRY before CLOCK waits safely; ending waits for feedback and committed movement (1.0808ms)
✔ all 49 starts move continuously via pickup and destination without rewriting player/grid state (27.7721ms)
✔ completion waits for delivery plus pause, emits once and large/small time steps agree (3.7561ms)
✔ town rendering is a bounded idempotent projection with readable prop identities (39.4716ms)
✔ one full board uses original cardinal movement and cannot leave any edge (6.832ms)
✔ all landmarks and every letter fit the fixed frame with no building covering a letter (66.3321ms)
✔ mouse/Space holds, WASD/arrows, release and blur keep original selection behavior (5.4583ms)
✔ town BREAD: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (7.8394ms)
✔ town COIN: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.2884ms)
✔ town SHOP: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (0.8676ms)
✔ town LETTER: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (0.7355ms)
✔ town CLOCK: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.0137ms)
✔ town CARRY: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.0061ms)
✔ town has four initial clues, prefix hints after dependencies and a scan that includes decoys (4.0792ms)
✔ town spawn is a decoy, diagonals fail, all quests complete in dependency order without cottage world changes (3.0529ms)
✔ two reachable support objectives require explicit inspection, grant once and preserve main state (3.5687ms)
✔ reward crystal only appears after inspection and clears with reward timer (12.4104ms)
✔ support definitions reject duplicate IDs and invalid rewards (0.9653ms)
✔ normalizes targets, submissions and completed words; rejects non-target English words (2.2839ms)
✔ all six real board paths resolve; correct tiles persist, cleanup allows reuse, duplicates do not progress (13.7585ms)
✔ backtrack does not validate before release; wrong and interrupted feedback preserve progress (1.2097ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: KEY (6.0113ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: LIGHT (0.9442ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: WATER (0.5825ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: BOOK (0.4554ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: DOOR (0.7466ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: OPEN (0.5249ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders converge, duplicate/wrong submissions and events never replay (121.4989ms)
✔ renderer projects supplied state safely and normal door opening animates (43.7375ms)
ℹ tests 118
ℹ suites 0
ℹ pass 118
ℹ fail 0
ℹ cancelled 0
ℹ skipped 0
ℹ todo 0
ℹ duration_ms 3931.4863
