
> word-search-adventure@0.0.0 test
> node --experimental-strip-types --test tests/*.test.mjs

✔ Stage 1 no longer grants walk-over shards anywhere on the board (3.8085ms)
✔ hint progresses, survives focus switch, caps before last letter and hides completed (1.2655ms)
✔ long hints never expose full spelling (0.5989ms)
✔ scan queries every matching tile including distractors, expires without mutating tile states (2.4594ms)
✔ invalid full input never charges; uppercase normalization accepts exactly ASCII letter (4.887ms)
✔ no shards and selection/feedback lock guard both request paths (0.7218ms)
✔ valid no-match scan costs one and active scans replace rather than stack (1.8313ms)
✔ actual stage transition carries player ledger and resets stage-owned assistance (1.6615ms)
✔ door reveal stays backed by full plaster on every frame; OPEN reveals an opaque recess (518.3761ms)
✔ perimeter meshes leave all letter footprints clear throughout room reactions at the fixed camera angle (848.4294ms)
✔ BOOK reacts across the shelf before the featured book, then settles without lighting other props (13.307ms)
✔ KEY materializes by the player and its world position converges on a moving player (9.402ms)
✔ forest props do not occlude board, player or feedback from the unchanged camera (129.8212ms)
✔ crossing landings leave the full reserved river span empty and stay clear of the grid (13.836ms)
KEY: (0,0) -> (0,1) -> (0,2)
LIGHT: (0,4) -> (1,4) -> (2,4) -> (3,4) -> (4,4)
WATER: (2,0) -> (2,1) -> (2,2) -> (3,2) -> (4,2)
BOOK: (4,0) -> (4,1) -> (5,1) -> (5,2)
DOOR: (3,6) -> (2,6) -> (1,6) -> (0,6)
OPEN: (5,3) -> (5,4) -> (6,4) -> (6,5)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: KEY (5.7307ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: LIGHT (0.6083ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: WATER (0.4561ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: BOOK (0.6766ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: DOOR (0.5878ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: OPEN (1.5383ms)
✔ cardinal neighbors only (0.5383ms)
✔ deterministic IDs and world/grid round trips at different cell sizes (5.0754ms)
✔ hover never overwrites selection; correct expires and reset cancels feedback (3.9107ms)
✔ malformed stage layout fails early (2.3947ms)
✔ one command interpolates then commits exactly one tile and stops (4.1397ms)
✔ reject diagonal, malformed and all four boundary commands (1.207ms)
✔ stage start validated and completion independent of update frequency (1.2112ms)
✔ keyboard press only, first event wins, no queue, aliases and teardown (1.7589ms)
✔ arrival builds KEY, backtracks; mid-step release submits only committed path (2.0233ms)
✔ OPEN locked, not remembered; DOOR unlocks once; presentation then discovered list (8.4781ms)
✔ malformed dependency data is rejected (1.0103ms)
✔ key flight is simulation-owned, once only, and completes after 1.8 seconds (1.0256ms)
✔ legacy exit helper remains isolated from the stage runtime (5.0046ms)
✔ key tracks player, shelf slides, lamps stagger, droplets end and healthy plant persists (64.2331ms)
✔ E input rejects repeat, typing and modifiers; release, blur and teardown work (1.9147ms)
✔ five available data-driven clues contain no own target; navigation wraps and preserves progress (4.5298ms)
✔ non-focused WATER completes; wrong and duplicate keep focus/progress and emit no completion (1.6045ms)
✔ focused completion waits for feedback, skips completed, supports revisiting and manual override (0.6042ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders complete exactly once with no stage transition (121.5601ms)
✔ quest policy rejects vocabulary words without a quest and malformed quest mappings (1.0173ms)
✔ river stays inside reserved zone, below land and clear of the letter grid (37.2707ms)
✔ flow advances gently, stays in water across wrap and releases owned GPU resources (52.2333ms)
✔ current-tile start, KEY, immutable submission and no double submit (5.4235ms)
✔ backtrack immediately, preserve invalid path, disallow reuse, recover (0.9023ms)
✔ coordinate tracking reads committed logical grid; hover cannot mutate path (1.3853ms)
✔ real input adapter: left mouse, capture, release outside, blur, visibility, cancel and teardown (3.3554ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; KEY last (8.3151ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; LIGHT last (1.6428ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; WATER last (5.3155ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; BOOK last (2.4122ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; OPEN last (1.2137ms)
✔ empty placeholder does not complete (0.669ms)
✔ transition locks, fades, disposes old state, mounts fresh state once, then fades in (2.1642ms)
✔ disposing during fade prevents mounting a new stage (0.6224ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: KEY (159.9238ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: LIGHT (111.6499ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: WATER (108.6795ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: BOOK (40.853ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: OPEN (33.4354ms)
✔ intro receives destination data and blocks mounting, duplicate next and start until it finishes (1.1085ms)
✔ disposing during intro prevents destination gameplay from mounting (0.8865ms)
✔ offset grid round trips, stays safely on main ground, and supports original movement (6.0049ms)
✔ river foundation and raised ground fit the unchanged camera without a crossing (79.253ms)
✔ CLIMB first does not strand unfinished words; readiness waits for reactions, feedback and a committed step (4.8008ms)
✔ all 49 grid starts walk through the bridge and root waypoints without teleporting or rewriting gameplay (45.969ms)
✔ ending can start safely from every existing traversal node; timing is frame-rate independent (5.4236ms)
✔ the existing completion overlay waits until summit arrival plus a 0.75-second pause, once only (2.4523ms)
✔ wood has distinct grain/edges; narrow rope bridge assembles existing boards and consumes the coil (70.4157ms)
✔ ending route stays on supporting geometry and within the unchanged desktop/narrow camera (104.4114ms)
✔ initial hidden locks, both material orders, Hint gates, construction completion and one-time NEW QUEST (11.1619ms)
✔ safe crossing, grid return, far-side routes, climb gate, summit height and invalid moves (2.2574ms)
✔ completion waits for final reactions, duplicate submissions/events do not replay, reset is fresh (1.9397ms)
✔ visual reactions consume the same planks, keep mesh count bounded, and reconstruct final state (50.0689ms)
✔ bridge and root route nodes have visible supporting surfaces; new geometry avoids letters (102.8466ms)
✔ RIVER emphasis changes currents temporarily without affecting movement; Stage 1 remains grid-only (6.1101ms)
✔ TREE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (8.5073ms)
✔ WOOD: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (1.0448ms)
✔ ROPE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (1.4978ms)
✔ RIVER: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (0.8537ms)
✔ BRIDGE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (0.853ms)
✔ CLIMB: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (0.6029ms)
✔ four initial clues, generic progressive hints after dependencies, scan includes every decoy R (2.3065ms)
✔ start is a decoy; diagonals rejected; forest reactions preserve the tested board (2.797ms)
✔ Space and mouse hold/release submit once, exclude each other, cancel on blur, dispose cleanly (2.9094ms)
✔ Stage 2 uses the existing intro flow to mount the Stage 3 vocabulary runtime (4.5028ms)
✔ frozen Stage 3.2 board, spawn, camera and layout remain unchanged (14.2086ms)
✔ initial hidden quests reject submissions/hints; independent scan; exact unlock banners (16.2573ms)
✔ reaction durations, duplicates, reset and no replay after completed submission (7.413ms)
✔ all 720 word attempt orders converge under existing dependency validation (274.7836ms)
✔ CARRY before CLOCK waits safely; ending waits for feedback and committed movement (0.9635ms)
✔ all 49 starts move continuously via pickup and destination without rewriting player/grid state (26.3277ms)
✔ completion waits for delivery plus pause, emits once and large/small time steps agree (3.4671ms)
✔ town rendering is a bounded idempotent projection with readable prop identities (44.5199ms)
✔ shop pulse, letter hover/receive and clock emphasis settle without accumulating transforms (13.9521ms)
✔ one full board uses original cardinal movement and cannot leave any edge (4.5877ms)
✔ all landmarks and every letter fit the fixed frame with no building covering a letter (93.092ms)
✔ mouse/Space holds, WASD/arrows, release and blur keep original selection behavior (7.0937ms)
✔ town BREAD: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (7.6705ms)
✔ town COIN: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (4.8793ms)
✔ town SHOP: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (0.8174ms)
✔ town LETTER: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (0.7246ms)
✔ town CLOCK: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (0.7486ms)
✔ town CARRY: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (0.7005ms)
✔ town has four initial clues, prefix hints after dependencies and a scan that includes decoys (3.2373ms)
✔ town spawn is a decoy, diagonals fail, all quests complete in dependency order without cottage world changes (2.9361ms)
✔ Stage 3 transitions through the existing intro to a vocabulary Stage 4 that waits for completion (6.7524ms)
✔ workshop fits desktop/narrow frames and leaves every letter surface unobstructed (123.6606ms)
✔ workshop GEAR: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (7.5644ms)
✔ workshop REPAIR: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (1.3163ms)
✔ workshop POWER: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (1.1462ms)
✔ workshop LEVER: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (0.8879ms)
✔ workshop START: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (1.0808ms)
✔ workshop STOP: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (0.8758ms)
✔ workshop progression with GEAR first; locked words never complete; STOP requires submission (16.4294ms)
✔ workshop progression with REPAIR first; locked words never complete; STOP requires submission (12.2948ms)
✔ workshop hints gate locked/completed quests and reveal prefixes; scan includes every matching decoy only temporarily (44.8507ms)
✔ workshop spawn reaches all 49 tiles; diagonal and loop reuse rejected; approved framing unchanged (4.4735ms)
✔ two reachable support objectives require explicit inspection, grant once and preserve main state (9.8156ms)
✔ reward crystal only appears after inspection and clears with reward timer (16.5288ms)
✔ support definitions reject duplicate IDs and invalid rewards (1.3304ms)
✔ normalizes targets, submissions and completed words; rejects non-target English words (2.3742ms)
✔ all six real board paths resolve; correct tiles persist, cleanup allows reuse, duplicates do not progress (9.405ms)
✔ backtrack does not validate before release; wrong and interrupted feedback preserve progress (1.4745ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: KEY (6.8525ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: LIGHT (0.6739ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: WATER (0.4896ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: BOOK (0.5432ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: DOOR (0.5177ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: OPEN (0.5697ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders converge, duplicate/wrong submissions and events never replay (88.1492ms)
✔ renderer projects supplied state safely and normal door opening animates (31.2909ms)
ℹ tests 131
ℹ suites 0
ℹ pass 131
ℹ fail 0
ℹ cancelled 0
ℹ skipped 0
ℹ todo 0
ℹ duration_ms 3084.3845
