
> word-search-adventure@0.0.0 test
> node --experimental-strip-types --test tests/*.test.mjs

✔ Stage 1 no longer grants walk-over shards anywhere on the board (5.0665ms)
✔ hint progresses, survives focus switch, caps before last letter and hides completed (1.2917ms)
✔ long hints never expose full spelling (2.9081ms)
✔ scan queries every matching tile including distractors, expires without mutating tile states (3.4129ms)
✔ invalid full input never charges; uppercase normalization accepts exactly ASCII letter (0.6702ms)
✔ no shards and selection/feedback lock guard both request paths (0.44ms)
✔ valid no-match scan costs one and active scans replace rather than stack (0.4211ms)
✔ actual stage transition carries player ledger and resets stage-owned assistance (1.0562ms)
✔ door reveal stays backed by full plaster on every frame; OPEN reveals an opaque recess (438.737ms)
✔ perimeter meshes leave all letter footprints clear throughout room reactions at the fixed camera angle (910.768ms)
✔ BOOK reacts across the shelf before the featured book, then settles without lighting other props (43.5088ms)
✔ KEY materializes by the player and its world position converges on a moving player (8.488ms)
✔ forest props do not occlude board, player or feedback from the unchanged camera (163.2131ms)
✔ crossing landings leave the full reserved river span empty and stay clear of the grid (11.4527ms)
KEY: (0,0) -> (0,1) -> (0,2)
LIGHT: (0,4) -> (1,4) -> (2,4) -> (3,4) -> (4,4)
WATER: (2,0) -> (2,1) -> (2,2) -> (3,2) -> (4,2)
BOOK: (4,0) -> (4,1) -> (5,1) -> (5,2)
DOOR: (3,6) -> (2,6) -> (1,6) -> (0,6)
OPEN: (5,3) -> (5,4) -> (6,4) -> (6,5)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: KEY (34.776ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: LIGHT (0.6392ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: WATER (0.4984ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: BOOK (5.969ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: DOOR (0.5147ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: OPEN (0.5402ms)
✔ cardinal neighbors only (0.9123ms)
✔ deterministic IDs and world/grid round trips at different cell sizes (4.4359ms)
✔ hover never overwrites selection; correct expires and reset cancels feedback (0.9571ms)
✔ malformed stage layout fails early (0.7515ms)
✔ one command interpolates then commits exactly one tile and stops (10.1303ms)
✔ reject diagonal, malformed and all four boundary commands (2.9476ms)
✔ stage start validated and completion independent of update frequency (1.6472ms)
✔ keyboard press only, first event wins, no queue, aliases and teardown (1.4479ms)
✔ arrival builds KEY, backtracks; mid-step release submits only committed path (7.5384ms)
✔ OPEN locked, not remembered; DOOR unlocks once; presentation then discovered list (6.0077ms)
✔ malformed dependency data is rejected (0.7828ms)
✔ key flight is simulation-owned, once only, and completes after 1.8 seconds (0.6873ms)
✔ legacy exit helper remains isolated from the stage runtime (1.5367ms)
✔ key tracks player, shelf slides, lamps stagger, droplets end and healthy plant persists (59.4035ms)
✔ E input rejects repeat, typing and modifiers; release, blur and teardown work (3.774ms)
✔ five available data-driven clues contain no own target; navigation wraps and preserves progress (4.7118ms)
✔ non-focused WATER completes; wrong and duplicate keep focus/progress and emit no completion (4.366ms)
✔ focused completion waits for feedback, skips completed, supports revisiting and manual override (0.6547ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders complete exactly once with no stage transition (198.0741ms)
✔ quest policy rejects vocabulary words without a quest and malformed quest mappings (2.4195ms)
✔ river stays inside reserved zone, below land and clear of the letter grid (17.3189ms)
✔ flow advances gently, stays in water across wrap and releases owned GPU resources (34.1527ms)
✔ current-tile start, KEY, immutable submission and no double submit (4.9648ms)
✔ backtrack immediately, preserve invalid path, disallow reuse, recover (4.0543ms)
✔ coordinate tracking reads committed logical grid; hover cannot mutate path (2.6787ms)
✔ real input adapter: left mouse, capture, release outside, blur, visibility, cancel and teardown (2.9426ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; KEY last (6.7684ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; LIGHT last (1.051ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; WATER last (0.684ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; BOOK last (25.8411ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; OPEN last (1.9167ms)
✔ empty placeholder does not complete (0.4427ms)
✔ transition locks, fades, disposes old state, mounts fresh state once, then fades in (4.853ms)
✔ disposing during fade prevents mounting a new stage (0.4721ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: KEY (146.9496ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: LIGHT (86.1369ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: WATER (49.1963ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: BOOK (37.6065ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: OPEN (77.1329ms)
✔ intro receives destination data and blocks mounting, duplicate next and start until it finishes (0.9561ms)
✔ disposing during intro prevents destination gameplay from mounting (0.5549ms)
✔ offset grid round trips, stays safely on main ground, and supports original movement (7.5528ms)
✔ river foundation and raised ground fit the unchanged camera without a crossing (104.1436ms)
✔ CLIMB first does not strand unfinished words; readiness waits for reactions, feedback and a committed step (5.5401ms)
✔ all 49 grid starts walk through the bridge and root waypoints without teleporting or rewriting gameplay (95.3865ms)
✔ ending can start safely from every existing traversal node; timing is frame-rate independent (13.4452ms)
✔ the existing completion overlay waits until summit arrival plus a 0.75-second pause, once only (1.9909ms)
✔ wood has distinct grain/edges; narrow rope bridge assembles existing boards and consumes the coil (86.5544ms)
✔ ending route stays on supporting geometry and within the unchanged desktop/narrow camera (121.6288ms)
✔ initial hidden locks, both material orders, Hint gates, construction completion and one-time NEW QUEST (26.2632ms)
✔ safe crossing, grid return, far-side routes, climb gate, summit height and invalid moves (2.9439ms)
✔ completion waits for final reactions, duplicate submissions/events do not replay, reset is fresh (1.8359ms)
✔ visual reactions consume the same planks, keep mesh count bounded, and reconstruct final state (53.6566ms)
✔ bridge and root route nodes have visible supporting surfaces; new geometry avoids letters (71.4235ms)
✔ RIVER emphasis changes currents temporarily without affecting movement; Stage 1 remains grid-only (8.2392ms)
✔ TREE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (7.4066ms)
✔ WOOD: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (3.6819ms)
✔ ROPE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (1.1366ms)
✔ RIVER: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (1.974ms)
✔ BRIDGE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (1.355ms)
✔ CLIMB: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (0.6256ms)
✔ four initial clues, generic progressive hints after dependencies, scan includes every decoy R (1.9728ms)
✔ start is a decoy; diagonals rejected; forest reactions preserve the tested board (2.0863ms)
✔ Space and mouse hold/release submit once, exclude each other, cancel on blur, dispose cleanly (2.2907ms)
✔ Stage 2 uses the existing intro flow to mount the Stage 3 vocabulary runtime (5.151ms)
✔ frozen Stage 3.2 board, spawn, camera and layout remain unchanged (3.142ms)
✔ initial hidden quests reject submissions/hints; independent scan; exact unlock banners (4.7511ms)
✔ reaction durations, duplicates, reset and no replay after completed submission (7.7136ms)
✔ all 720 word attempt orders converge under existing dependency validation (231.8413ms)
✔ CARRY before CLOCK waits safely; ending waits for feedback and committed movement (1.0208ms)
✔ all 49 starts move continuously via pickup and destination without rewriting player/grid state (78.1981ms)
✔ completion waits for delivery plus pause, emits once and large/small time steps agree (2.2068ms)
✔ town rendering is a bounded idempotent projection with readable prop identities (231.4177ms)
✔ shop pulse, letter hover/receive and clock emphasis settle without accumulating transforms (11.8973ms)
✔ one full board uses original cardinal movement and cannot leave any edge (4.9169ms)
✔ all landmarks and every letter fit the fixed frame with no building covering a letter (108.2952ms)
✔ mouse/Space holds, WASD/arrows, release and blur keep original selection behavior (7.9958ms)
✔ town BREAD: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (19.6993ms)
✔ town COIN: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.5064ms)
✔ town SHOP: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.1151ms)
✔ town LETTER: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (5.971ms)
✔ town CLOCK: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (13.2684ms)
✔ town CARRY: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.1522ms)
✔ town has four initial clues, prefix hints after dependencies and a scan that includes decoys (5.7289ms)
✔ town spawn is a decoy, diagonals fail, all quests complete in dependency order without cottage world changes (26.2032ms)
✔ Stage 3 transitions through the existing intro to a vocabulary Stage 4 that waits for completion (7.8257ms)
✔ workshop fits desktop/narrow frames and leaves every letter surface unobstructed (387.5473ms)
✔ workshop sequence GEAR then REPAIR: delayed STOP, smooth shutdown, once-only completion (142.6367ms)
✔ workshop sequence REPAIR then GEAR: delayed STOP, smooth shutdown, once-only completion (64.8262ms)
✔ workshop reveal waits for actual completion plus 0.45 seconds and ignores invalid dt (4.7415ms)
✔ workshop renderer projects all phases without state mutation, keeps crates on output, and preserves grid visibility (395.518ms)
✔ polish: local gear emphasis, repair transform and sequential power arrival (10.1511ms)
✔ notification overlay hides a queued banner while reactions hold it and resumes afterward (5.0784ms)
✔ workshop GEAR: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (21.3504ms)
✔ workshop REPAIR: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (13.3043ms)
✔ workshop POWER: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (34.8166ms)
✔ workshop LEVER: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (12.939ms)
✔ workshop START: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (22.1504ms)
✔ workshop STOP: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (28.544ms)
✔ workshop progression with GEAR first; locked words never complete; STOP requires submission (80.7148ms)
✔ workshop progression with REPAIR first; locked words never complete; STOP requires submission (114.334ms)
✔ workshop hints gate locked/completed quests and reveal prefixes; scan includes every matching decoy only temporarily (11.354ms)
✔ workshop spawn reaches all 49 tiles; diagonal and loop reuse rejected; approved framing unchanged (2.3331ms)
✔ two reachable support objectives require explicit inspection, grant once and preserve main state (5.4436ms)
✔ reward crystal only appears after inspection and clears with reward timer (8.7746ms)
✔ support definitions reject duplicate IDs and invalid rewards (1.0842ms)
✔ normalizes targets, submissions and completed words; rejects non-target English words (1.9163ms)
✔ all six real board paths resolve; correct tiles persist, cleanup allows reuse, duplicates do not progress (9.6789ms)
✔ backtrack does not validate before release; wrong and interrupted feedback preserve progress (1.1379ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: KEY (3.453ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: LIGHT (1.1384ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: WATER (1.1653ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: BOOK (0.7502ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: DOOR (0.8807ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: OPEN (0.5167ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders converge, duplicate/wrong submissions and events never replay (102.8813ms)
✔ renderer projects supplied state safely and normal door opening animates (33.4925ms)
ℹ tests 137
ℹ suites 0
ℹ pass 137
ℹ fail 0
ℹ cancelled 0
ℹ skipped 0
ℹ todo 0
ℹ duration_ms 4115.7024
