
> word-search-adventure@0.0.0 test
> node --experimental-strip-types --test tests/*.test.mjs

✔ Stage 1 no longer grants walk-over shards anywhere on the board (63.9114ms)
✔ hint progresses, survives focus switch, caps before last letter and hides completed (45.8309ms)
✔ long hints never expose full spelling (1.1705ms)
✔ scan queries every matching tile including distractors, expires without mutating tile states (12.0886ms)
✔ invalid full input never charges; uppercase normalization accepts exactly ASCII letter (1.2707ms)
✔ no shards and selection/feedback lock guard both request paths (5.2189ms)
✔ valid no-match scan costs one and active scans replace rather than stack (3.1578ms)
✔ actual stage transition carries player ledger and resets stage-owned assistance (11.3019ms)
✔ door reveal stays backed by full plaster on every frame; OPEN reveals an opaque recess (4289.093ms)
✔ perimeter meshes leave all letter footprints clear throughout room reactions at the fixed camera angle (5115.2842ms)
✔ BOOK reacts across the shelf before the featured book, then settles without lighting other props (137.8257ms)
✔ KEY materializes by the player and its world position converges on a moving player (63.9853ms)
✔ forest props do not occlude board, player or feedback from the unchanged camera (1355.6257ms)
✔ crossing landings leave the full reserved river span empty and stay clear of the grid (76.6571ms)
KEY: (0,0) -> (0,1) -> (0,2)
LIGHT: (0,4) -> (1,4) -> (2,4) -> (3,4) -> (4,4)
WATER: (2,0) -> (2,1) -> (2,2) -> (3,2) -> (4,2)
BOOK: (4,0) -> (4,1) -> (5,1) -> (5,2)
DOOR: (3,6) -> (2,6) -> (1,6) -> (0,6)
OPEN: (5,3) -> (5,4) -> (6,4) -> (6,5)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: KEY (17.5086ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: LIGHT (0.7898ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: WATER (8.5985ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: BOOK (1.8488ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: DOOR (2.934ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: OPEN (24.6721ms)
✔ cardinal neighbors only (7.3914ms)
✔ deterministic IDs and world/grid round trips at different cell sizes (24.1416ms)
✔ hover never overwrites selection; correct expires and reset cancels feedback (19.2026ms)
✔ malformed stage layout fails early (6.6664ms)
✔ one command interpolates then commits exactly one tile and stops (15.7659ms)
✔ reject diagonal, malformed and all four boundary commands (6.661ms)
✔ stage start validated and completion independent of update frequency (27.5817ms)
✔ keyboard press only, first event wins, no queue, aliases and teardown (52.4098ms)
✔ arrival builds KEY, backtracks; mid-step release submits only committed path (25.8909ms)
✔ OPEN locked, not remembered; DOOR unlocks once; presentation then discovered list (6.9637ms)
✔ malformed dependency data is rejected (2.9341ms)
✔ key flight is simulation-owned, once only, and completes after 1.8 seconds (4.3316ms)
✔ legacy exit helper remains isolated from the stage runtime (7.0277ms)
✔ key tracks player, shelf slides, lamps stagger, droplets end and healthy plant persists (297.1244ms)
✔ E input rejects repeat, typing and modifiers; release, blur and teardown work (2.9476ms)
✔ five available data-driven clues contain no own target; navigation wraps and preserves progress (8.3043ms)
✔ non-focused WATER completes; wrong and duplicate keep focus/progress and emit no completion (10.6591ms)
✔ focused completion waits for feedback, skips completed, supports revisiting and manual override (2.3344ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders complete exactly once with no stage transition (879.8597ms)
✔ quest policy rejects vocabulary words without a quest and malformed quest mappings (6.4186ms)
✔ river stays inside reserved zone, below land and clear of the letter grid (65.0914ms)
✔ flow advances gently, stays in water across wrap and releases owned GPU resources (22.0275ms)
✔ current-tile start, KEY, immutable submission and no double submit (8.7842ms)
✔ backtrack immediately, preserve invalid path, disallow reuse, recover (1.1376ms)
✔ coordinate tracking reads committed logical grid; hover cannot mutate path (3.519ms)
✔ real input adapter: left mouse, capture, release outside, blur, visibility, cancel and teardown (3.2492ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; KEY last (61.2269ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; LIGHT last (1.6772ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; WATER last (3.7403ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; BOOK last (2.0636ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; OPEN last (2.4876ms)
✔ empty placeholder does not complete (2.0191ms)
✔ transition locks, fades, disposes old state, mounts fresh state once, then fades in (50.3642ms)
✔ disposing during fade prevents mounting a new stage (3.3201ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: KEY (950.2039ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: LIGHT (1224.9157ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: WATER (449.753ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: BOOK (161.0566ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: OPEN (281.8836ms)
✔ intro receives destination data and blocks mounting, duplicate next and start until it finishes (9.8442ms)
✔ disposing during intro prevents destination gameplay from mounting (4.3385ms)
✔ offset grid round trips, stays safely on main ground, and supports original movement (33.0838ms)
✔ river foundation and raised ground fit the unchanged camera without a crossing (866.9159ms)
✔ CLIMB first does not strand unfinished words; readiness waits for reactions, feedback and a committed step (106.972ms)
✔ all 49 grid starts walk through the bridge and root waypoints without teleporting or rewriting gameplay (784.0332ms)
✔ ending can start safely from every existing traversal node; timing is frame-rate independent (163.3526ms)
✔ the existing completion overlay waits until summit arrival plus a 0.75-second pause, once only (22.7697ms)
✔ wood has distinct grain/edges; narrow rope bridge assembles existing boards and consumes the coil (1044.9601ms)
✔ ending route stays on supporting geometry and within the unchanged desktop/narrow camera (704.5639ms)
✔ initial hidden locks, both material orders, Hint gates, construction completion and one-time NEW QUEST (69.6166ms)
✔ safe crossing, grid return, far-side routes, climb gate, summit height and invalid moves (14.1421ms)
✔ completion waits for final reactions, duplicate submissions/events do not replay, reset is fresh (117.0833ms)
✔ visual reactions consume the same planks, keep mesh count bounded, and reconstruct final state (757.2231ms)
✔ bridge and root route nodes have visible supporting surfaces; new geometry avoids letters (1175.3285ms)
✔ RIVER emphasis changes currents temporarily without affecting movement; Stage 1 remains grid-only (40.3099ms)
✔ TREE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (36.5972ms)
✔ WOOD: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (3.0124ms)
✔ ROPE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (67.4542ms)
✔ RIVER: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (33.9973ms)
✔ BRIDGE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (11.9319ms)
✔ CLIMB: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (11.6589ms)
✔ four initial clues, generic progressive hints after dependencies, scan includes every decoy R (53.2161ms)
✔ start is a decoy; diagonals rejected; forest reactions preserve the tested board (60.3136ms)
✔ Space and mouse hold/release submit once, exclude each other, cancel on blur, dispose cleanly (176.5204ms)
✔ Stage 2 uses the existing intro flow to mount the Stage 3 vocabulary runtime (20.7226ms)
✔ one full board uses original cardinal movement and cannot leave any edge (58.6524ms)
✔ all landmarks and every letter fit the fixed frame with no building covering a letter (265.0792ms)
✔ mouse/Space holds, WASD/arrows, release and blur keep original selection behavior (29.735ms)
✔ town BREAD: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (65.7252ms)
✔ town COIN: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.5796ms)
✔ town SHOP: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.9344ms)
✔ town LETTER: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.2241ms)
✔ town CLOCK: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.2231ms)
✔ town CARRY: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.5407ms)
✔ town has six available clues, prefix hints for every word and a scan that includes decoys (4.5808ms)
✔ town spawn is a decoy, diagonals fail, all quests complete in reverse order without world changes (9.1167ms)
✔ two reachable support objectives require explicit inspection, grant once and preserve main state (6.9612ms)
✔ reward crystal only appears after inspection and clears with reward timer (16.0606ms)
✔ support definitions reject duplicate IDs and invalid rewards (2.8411ms)
✔ normalizes targets, submissions and completed words; rejects non-target English words (6.5487ms)
✔ all six real board paths resolve; correct tiles persist, cleanup allows reuse, duplicates do not progress (35.1591ms)
✔ backtrack does not validate before release; wrong and interrupted feedback preserve progress (6.4592ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: KEY (18.2385ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: LIGHT (8.3929ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: WATER (10.8448ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: BOOK (4.213ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: DOOR (1.2782ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: OPEN (4.1193ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders converge, duplicate/wrong submissions and events never replay (367.1347ms)
✔ renderer projects supplied state safely and normal door opening animates (165.1465ms)
ℹ tests 110
ℹ suites 0
ℹ pass 110
ℹ fail 0
ℹ cancelled 0
ℹ skipped 0
ℹ todo 0
ℹ duration_ms 12945.7526
