
> word-search-adventure@0.0.0 test
> node --experimental-strip-types --test tests/*.test.mjs

✔ Stage 1 no longer grants walk-over shards anywhere on the board (4.7411ms)
✔ hint progresses, survives focus switch, caps before last letter and hides completed (1.2077ms)
✔ long hints never expose full spelling (0.5809ms)
✔ scan queries every matching tile including distractors, expires without mutating tile states (2.3657ms)
✔ invalid full input never charges; uppercase normalization accepts exactly ASCII letter (0.7453ms)
✔ no shards and selection/feedback lock guard both request paths (0.5912ms)
✔ valid no-match scan costs one and active scans replace rather than stack (0.5411ms)
✔ actual stage transition carries player ledger and resets stage-owned assistance (2.0245ms)
✔ door reveal stays backed by full plaster on every frame; OPEN reveals an opaque recess (585.0604ms)
✔ perimeter meshes leave all letter footprints clear throughout room reactions at the fixed camera angle (929.1689ms)
✔ BOOK reacts across the shelf before the featured book, then settles without lighting other props (31.9755ms)
✔ KEY materializes by the player and its world position converges on a moving player (9.0974ms)
✔ forest props do not occlude board, player or feedback from the unchanged camera (150.6661ms)
✔ crossing landings leave the full reserved river span empty and stay clear of the grid (11.1464ms)
KEY: (0,0) -> (0,1) -> (0,2)
LIGHT: (0,4) -> (1,4) -> (2,4) -> (3,4) -> (4,4)
WATER: (2,0) -> (2,1) -> (2,2) -> (3,2) -> (4,2)
BOOK: (4,0) -> (4,1) -> (5,1) -> (5,2)
DOOR: (3,6) -> (2,6) -> (1,6) -> (0,6)
OPEN: (5,3) -> (5,4) -> (6,4) -> (6,5)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: KEY (4.8083ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: LIGHT (5.4361ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: WATER (0.7426ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: BOOK (3.3988ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: DOOR (0.4757ms)
✔ Stage 1 contains cardinal path: OPEN (0.4768ms)
✔ cardinal neighbors only (0.377ms)
✔ deterministic IDs and world/grid round trips at different cell sizes (4.2885ms)
✔ hover never overwrites selection; correct expires and reset cancels feedback (2.2062ms)
✔ malformed stage layout fails early (1.2485ms)
✔ one command interpolates then commits exactly one tile and stops (8.1706ms)
✔ reject diagonal, malformed and all four boundary commands (1.1357ms)
✔ stage start validated and completion independent of update frequency (1.4309ms)
✔ keyboard press only, first event wins, no queue, aliases and teardown (1.7753ms)
✔ arrival builds KEY, backtracks; mid-step release submits only committed path (1.8948ms)
✔ OPEN locked, not remembered; DOOR unlocks once; presentation then discovered list (13.3815ms)
✔ malformed dependency data is rejected (0.8411ms)
✔ key flight is simulation-owned, once only, and completes after 1.8 seconds (5.1863ms)
✔ legacy exit helper remains isolated from the stage runtime (15.9985ms)
✔ key tracks player, shelf slides, lamps stagger, droplets end and healthy plant persists (147.9176ms)
✔ E input rejects repeat, typing and modifiers; release, blur and teardown work (8.6675ms)
✔ five available data-driven clues contain no own target; navigation wraps and preserves progress (6.6998ms)
✔ non-focused WATER completes; wrong and duplicate keep focus/progress and emit no completion (20.1241ms)
✔ focused completion waits for feedback, skips completed, supports revisiting and manual override (0.7047ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders complete exactly once with no stage transition (194.1645ms)
✔ quest policy rejects vocabulary words without a quest and malformed quest mappings (0.9957ms)
✔ river stays inside reserved zone, below land and clear of the letter grid (41.464ms)
✔ flow advances gently, stays in water across wrap and releases owned GPU resources (30.8404ms)
✔ current-tile start, KEY, immutable submission and no double submit (4.9271ms)
✔ backtrack immediately, preserve invalid path, disallow reuse, recover (0.6693ms)
✔ coordinate tracking reads committed logical grid; hover cannot mutate path (0.7513ms)
✔ real input adapter: left mouse, capture, release outside, blur, visibility, cancel and teardown (3.1859ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; KEY last (9.2706ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; LIGHT last (1.1842ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; WATER last (0.6767ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; BOOK last (0.7858ms)
✔ completion waits for every quest and reaction; OPEN last (0.6029ms)
✔ empty placeholder does not complete (0.3458ms)
✔ transition locks, fades, disposes old state, mounts fresh state once, then fades in (24.9353ms)
✔ disposing during fade prevents mounting a new stage (0.6395ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: KEY (200.8645ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: LIGHT (63.6674ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: WATER (33.0536ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: BOOK (71.9863ms)
✔ real reaction settles before completion: OPEN (85.0849ms)
✔ intro receives destination data and blocks mounting, duplicate next and start until it finishes (1.4822ms)
✔ disposing during intro prevents destination gameplay from mounting (0.6481ms)
✔ offset grid round trips, stays safely on main ground, and supports original movement (9.4446ms)
✔ river foundation and raised ground fit the unchanged camera without a crossing (181.474ms)
✔ CLIMB first does not strand unfinished words; readiness waits for reactions, feedback and a committed step (5.2991ms)
✔ all 49 grid starts walk through the bridge and root waypoints without teleporting or rewriting gameplay (78.0612ms)
✔ ending can start safely from every existing traversal node; timing is frame-rate independent (11.368ms)
✔ the existing completion overlay waits until summit arrival plus a 0.75-second pause, once only (1.8093ms)
✔ wood has distinct grain/edges; narrow rope bridge assembles existing boards and consumes the coil (69.6553ms)
✔ ending route stays on supporting geometry and within the unchanged desktop/narrow camera (95.0333ms)
✔ initial hidden locks, both material orders, Hint gates, construction completion and one-time NEW QUEST (11.0102ms)
✔ safe crossing, grid return, far-side routes, climb gate, summit height and invalid moves (2.5615ms)
✔ completion waits for final reactions, duplicate submissions/events do not replay, reset is fresh (1.7299ms)
✔ visual reactions consume the same planks, keep mesh count bounded, and reconstruct final state (50.9902ms)
✔ bridge and root route nodes have visible supporting surfaces; new geometry avoids letters (107.7119ms)
✔ RIVER emphasis changes currents temporarily without affecting movement; Stage 1 remains grid-only (4.845ms)
✔ TREE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (6.5604ms)
✔ WOOD: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (1.2764ms)
✔ ROPE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (1.0775ms)
✔ RIVER: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (1.6025ms)
✔ BRIDGE: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (1.8434ms)
✔ CLIMB: unique orthogonal solution, backtracking and real quest submission (0.9279ms)
✔ four initial clues, generic progressive hints after dependencies, scan includes every decoy R (2.1137ms)
✔ start is a decoy; diagonals rejected; forest reactions preserve the tested board (2.3685ms)
✔ Space and mouse hold/release submit once, exclude each other, cancel on blur, dispose cleanly (2.0609ms)
✔ Stage 2 uses the existing intro flow to mount the Stage 3 vocabulary runtime (8.4234ms)
✔ frozen Stage 3.2 board, spawn, camera and layout remain unchanged (10.202ms)
✔ initial hidden quests reject submissions/hints; independent scan; exact unlock banners (14.4118ms)
✔ reaction durations, duplicates, reset and no replay after completed submission (5.0737ms)
✔ all 720 word attempt orders converge under existing dependency validation (218.5434ms)
✔ CARRY before CLOCK waits safely; ending waits for feedback and committed movement (29.7898ms)
✔ all 49 starts move continuously via pickup and destination without rewriting player/grid state (55.7162ms)
✔ completion waits for delivery plus pause, emits once and large/small time steps agree (1.9047ms)
✔ town rendering is a bounded idempotent projection with readable prop identities (52.0032ms)
✔ shop pulse, letter hover/receive and clock emphasis settle without accumulating transforms (26.9226ms)
✔ one full board uses original cardinal movement and cannot leave any edge (5.2089ms)
✔ all landmarks and every letter fit the fixed frame with no building covering a letter (108.6765ms)
✔ mouse/Space holds, WASD/arrows, release and blur keep original selection behavior (28.3007ms)
✔ town BREAD: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (7.0396ms)
✔ town COIN: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (0.8545ms)
✔ town SHOP: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (0.6371ms)
✔ town LETTER: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (6.7343ms)
✔ town CLOCK: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (1.6504ms)
✔ town CARRY: exactly one cardinal path, backtracking, valid submission, persistent tiles (0.7385ms)
✔ town has four initial clues, prefix hints after dependencies and a scan that includes decoys (4.2153ms)
✔ town spawn is a decoy, diagonals fail, all quests complete in dependency order without cottage world changes (10.6648ms)
✔ Stage 3 transitions through the existing intro to a vocabulary Stage 4 that waits for completion (4.5376ms)
✔ workshop fits desktop/narrow frames and leaves every letter surface unobstructed (124.2501ms)
✔ workshop sequence GEAR then REPAIR: delayed STOP, smooth shutdown, once-only completion (55.7942ms)
✔ workshop sequence REPAIR then GEAR: delayed STOP, smooth shutdown, once-only completion (64.1467ms)
✔ workshop reveal waits for actual completion plus 0.45 seconds and ignores invalid dt (15.2949ms)
✔ workshop renderer projects all phases without state mutation, keeps crates on output, and preserves grid visibility (506.8262ms)
✔ polish: local gear emphasis, repair transform and sequential power arrival (21.0892ms)
✔ notification overlay hides a queued banner while reactions hold it and resumes afterward (7.817ms)
✔ finale waits for visible word feedback, locks immediately, holds idle and preserves output until disposal (35.4798ms)
✔ Stage 4 Next Stage uses fade/dispose/Stage 5 intro/mount/fade without reloading (27.6314ms)
✔ workshop GEAR: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (16.4685ms)
✔ workshop REPAIR: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (15.9019ms)
✔ workshop POWER: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (14.2043ms)
✔ workshop LEVER: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (14.279ms)
✔ workshop START: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (18.7345ms)
✔ workshop STOP: unique path, movement, backtracking and persistent completed tiles (38.1166ms)
✔ workshop progression with GEAR first; locked words never complete; STOP requires submission (56.2998ms)
✔ workshop progression with REPAIR first; locked words never complete; STOP requires submission (52.3332ms)
✔ workshop hints gate locked/completed quests and reveal prefixes; scan includes every matching decoy only temporarily (16.815ms)
✔ workshop spawn reaches all 49 tiles; diagonal and loop reuse rejected; approved framing unchanged (2.9816ms)
✔ storm clearing fits desktop/narrow frames and leaves every letter surface unobstructed (102.4624ms)
✔ Stage 5 stays a scenery blockout with no quests, reactions or completion (36.4264ms)
✔ two reachable support objectives require explicit inspection, grant once and preserve main state (4.6352ms)
✔ reward crystal only appears after inspection and clears with reward timer (16.5043ms)
✔ support definitions reject duplicate IDs and invalid rewards (2.5779ms)
✔ normalizes targets, submissions and completed words; rejects non-target English words (2.0801ms)
✔ all six real board paths resolve; correct tiles persist, cleanup allows reuse, duplicates do not progress (9.6505ms)
✔ backtrack does not validate before release; wrong and interrupted feedback preserve progress (1.6651ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: KEY (7.7533ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: LIGHT (1.6339ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: WATER (1.5393ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: BOOK (1.6601ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: DOOR (1.2037ms)
✔ movement + selection + quest + reaction: OPEN (0.8147ms)
✔ all 720 quest orders converge, duplicate/wrong submissions and events never replay (132.2174ms)
✔ renderer projects supplied state safely and normal door opening animates (45.0286ms)
ℹ tests 141
ℹ suites 0
ℹ pass 141
ℹ fail 0
ℹ cancelled 0
ℹ skipped 0
ℹ todo 0
ℹ duration_ms 3470.1545
